Imagine yourself as a marketing manager at Parch and Posey.
تخيل أنك مدير التسويق في Parch &amp; Posey.
You want to compare Facebook as a marketing channel against all other channels.
وتريد مقارنة Facebook كقناة تسويق بكل القنوات الأخرى.
You know Facebook is a great channel for your business but,
تعرف أن Facebook قناة جيدة لعملك لكن،
is it better than all the rest combined?
هل هو أفضل من باقي القنوات مجتمعين؟
Let's find out. In order to do this,
لنكتشف الأمر. لفعل ذلك،
you'll need to create a derived column.
ستحتاج لإنشاء عمود مشتق.
That means you'll take data from existing columns and modify it.
وذلك يعني أنك ستأخذ بيانات من أعمدة موجودة وتعدلها.
In previous lessons, we did this using arithmetic.
في الدروس السابقة، قمنا بذلك باستخدام العمليات الحسابية.
For this application, we use
في هذا التطبيق، نستخدم
the "CASE" statement which is sequel's way of handling "IF" "then" logic.
عبارة "CASE" التي هي طريقة SQL للتعامل مع منطق "IF" "then".
The case statement is followed by at least one pair of "WHEN" and "THEN" statements.
يتبع عبارة case زوج واحد على الأقل من العبارتين "WHEN" و "THEN".
Sequel's equivalent of "IF" "THEN".
SQL's يعادل "IF" "THEN".
It must finish with the word "END".
يجب ان تنتهي بكلمة "END".
the conditional statement "channel equals Facebook" is true.
إذا كانت العبارة الشرطية "channel equals Facebook" صحيحة.
If so, it results in the value "yes" being printed in the column "is_Facebook".
وإذا كانت كذلك، ينتج عنها القيمة "yes" تظهر في العمود "is_Facebook".
If not, that Rose value in the is_Facebook column is left "no".
وإذا لم تكن كذلك، ستبقى هذه القيمة الوردية في العمود is_Facebook "no".
This query makes it pretty easy to see what's happening because we've
هذا الاستعلام يجعل الأمر سهلاً لنرى ما يحدث
included the case statement along with the channel column itself.
لأننا أدخلنا عبارة case مع عمود القناة.
You can check each row to see whether channel
يمكنك فحص كل صف لترى إذا كانت القناة تستوفي
meets the condition "channel equals Facebook",
الشرط "channel equals Facebook",
and then see the result in the column generated using the case statement.
ثم ترى النتيجة في العمود يتم إنشائها باستخدام عبارة case.
Now, what we'd really like this query to do is fill in those nulls with the word "no".
الآن، ما نريد أن يفعله هذا الاستعلام هو ملء هذه الحقول الفارغة بالكلمة "no".
We can do this with the L statement which provides a way to capture values
يمكننا فعل ذلك بعبارة L التي تقدم طريقة لمراقبة القيم
not specified in "WHEN" "THEN" statements.
غير المحددة في عبارات "WHEN" "THEN".
If we want this new column to keep track of not just our
إذا أردنا هذا العمود الجديد ألا يتبع فقط
Facebook channel but also the direct channel,
قناة Facebook، ولكن القناة المباشرة أيضًا،
we could change our case statement to use the "OR" operator.
يمكننا أن نغير عبارة الحالة لدينا لاستخدام مشغل "OR".
a logical condition similar to what you would put in a "WHERE" clause.
شرطًا منطقيًا مشابهًا لما ستضعه في أداة الربط "WHERE".
So you can use "END like END" or any other operators you've already seen.
لذا يمكنك استخدام المشغل "END like END" أو أي مشغلات أخرى شاهدته.
Imagine yourself in operations at Parch and Posey.
تخيل أنك تعمل في قسم العمليات في Parch &amp; Posey.
You'd like to classify orders into general groups based on
وتود تصنيف الطلبيات لمجموعات عامة بناء على
order size to get even more granular about inventory planning.
حجم الطلبية حتى تصبح تفصيلية أكثر فيما يتعلق بالتخطيط للجرد.
You can use a case statement to define a number of
يمكنك استخدام عبارة حالة لتحديد عدد
outcomes by including as many "WHEN" "THEN" statements as you'd like.
النتائج عن طريق إدراج كثير من عبارات "WHEN" "THEN" قدر ما تشاء.
will get evaluated in the order that they're written.
ستخضع للتقييم بحسب الترتيب التي كتبت به.
So, if the value in the total column of a given row is 600,
فإذا كانت القيمة في العمود الإجمالي لصف متاح هي
it will produce a result of over 500.
فسوف ينشأ عنها نتيجة أكثر من 500
the database will first check to see if the total is
ستتفقد قاعدة البيانات أولًا لمعرفة ما إذا كان الإجمالي
greater than 500 because that's the first "WHEN" statement.
أكبر من 500 لأن هذه هي أول عبارة "WHEN"
169 is not greater than 500,
169 ليست أكبر من 500
so we'll move on to evaluate the next "WHEN.
لذا سنتابع لتقييم عبارة "WHEN" التالية.
This process continues until a logical "WHEN" statement evaluates to
تستمر هذه العملية حتى يصبح تقييم عبارة "WHEN"
true in which case the "THEN" statement will be recorded in the total group column.
صحيحًا في حال تم تسجيل عبارة "THEN" في عمود المجموعة الإجمالي.
For 169, this would happen when the "WHEN" statement results in 101 to 300.
بالنسبة ل169، سيحدث ذلك حين ينتج عن عبارة "WHEN" 101 إلى 300.
While the above works, it's really best to create "WHEN" statements that don't overlap.
وبينما ينجح الأمر، سيكون من الأفضل حقًا إنشاء عبارات "WHEN" لا تتداخل.
The conditional statement "when total is greater than 500" overlaps with the statement
تتداخل العبارة الشرطية "عندما يكون الإجمالي أكبر من 500" مع العبارة
"when total is greater than 300" for
"حين يكون الإجمالي أكبر من 300"
every value greater than 500 which is a little confusing.
لكل قيمة أكبر من 500 وهو أمر محير.
A better way to write the above would be to
الطريقة الأفضل لكتابة ما سبق هي
define specific groups that don't overlap with one another.
تحديد مجموعات خاصة لا تتداخل مع بعضها البعض.
You can do this by stringing together multiple conditional statements
يمكنك القيام بذلك بجمع عدة عبارات شرطية معًا
with "END" and "OR" the same way you might in a "WHERE" clause.
مع "END" و"OR" بنفس الطريقة التي تقوم بها مع أداة الربط "WHERE".
we'll take these casements just one step further by
سنأخذ هذه النوافذ إلى خطوة أخرى
combining them with aggregations that we looked at earlier.
بجمعها مع تجميعات تعاملنا معها مسبقًا.